[Music]
[音乐]
Welcome! In the last lecture, we successfully filtered out the hopping direction from player's input.
欢迎!在上一节课中，我们成功地从玩家的输入中过滤出了跳跃的方向。
And now, with this ready, the next thing that I want to do, I'm going to get hold of the hopping animations that we need.
现在，准备好了，下一件我想做的事情，我将获得我们需要的跳跃动画。
So go back to Mixamo, in the search box here, I'm going to search "hang", and you can see in here we have this brace hang hop up.
所以回到Mixamo，在这里的搜索框中，我要搜索“挂起”，你可以看到在这里我们有这个支架挂起。
So this is the one that we're going to get. And same as usual, there isn't an "in place" option in here.
所以这就是我们要得到的。和往常一样，这里没有“就地”选项。
That means we'll need to adjust this animation in Control Rake. So I'm going to download it.
这意味着我们需要在Control Rake中调整这个动画。所以我要下载它。
And make sure "select without skin", and click "download".
并确保“选择无皮肤”，点击“下载”。
So this is hopping up, and I'm going to download this brace hang drop. So we can use this to hop down.
所以这是跳起来的，我要下载这个支撑吊点。所以我们可以用这个跳下去。
I'm going to click "download".
我要点击“下载”。
So these are the animations that I just downloaded from Mixamo. If you'd like to catch up with me, you can pause the video now and give this a go.
这些是我刚刚从Mixamo下载的动画。如果你想跟上我，你现在可以暂停视频，然后试一试。
Welcome back! And now we'll need to retarget these animations.
欢迎回来！现在我们需要重新定位这些动画。
So I'm going to select this brace hang hop up and this brace hang drop. I'm going to copy them.
所以我要选择这个支撑吊点和这个支撑吊点。我要把它们复制下来。
Then I'm going to go inside of this incoming FBX, double click to open it.
然后我要进入这个传入的FBX，双击打开它。
I've already cleared this folder, so I'm going to paste my animations in here.
我已经清除了这个文件夹，所以我要将我的动画粘贴到这里。
Then I'm going to double click to open this Mixamo converter. Left click to continue, and enter the conversion process.
然后我要双击打开这个Mixamo转换器。左键点击继续，进入转换过程。
Scroll down, click this button here to convert the animations.
向下滚动，单击此处以转换动画。
Then click this button here to open the folder. And these are my converted animations.
然后点击此处打开该文件夹。这些是我改编的动画。
So with these two animations selected, I'm going to drag them to my content browser.
选中这两个动画后，我将把它们拖到我的内容浏览器中。
And select the skeleton in here. And click "inport all".
然后选择这里的骨架。并点击“全部导入”。
And there you go. These are the raw animations that we can use later.
这就对了。这些是我们以后可以使用的原始动画。
So this is for hopping down, this one is for hopping up.
这个是用来跳下来的，这个是用来跳上来的。
One thing here that you need to be careful with, so this animation here has the same name as the animation that we use to exit our climb state.
这里需要注意的一件事是，这个动画与我们用来退出爬升状态的动画具有相同的名称。
So you can see it's also called this brace hang drop. If I double click to open this one.
所以你可以看到它也被称为支撑吊坠。如果我双击打开这个。
So make sure you rename your hop down animation before you move it to this raw folder.
因此，在将其移动到这个原始文件夹之前，请确保重命名您的跳下动画。
So I'm going to go back to my content browser. I'm going to change this name to hop down underscore raw.
因此，我将返回到我的内容浏览器。我要把这个名字改成下划线RAW。
Alright, I'm going to select these two animations and I'm going to move them to this raw folder. Select "move here".
好的，我将选择这两个动画，并将它们移动到这个原始文件夹中。选择“移至此处”。
And go to file, click "save all". And next thing, same as what we've done before, we'll need to fix their root motion.
并转到文件，单击“全部保存”。下一步，和我们之前所做的一样，我们需要修正它们的根运动。
So I'm going to first double click to open this brace hang hop up and click this root bone.
所以我要先双击打开这个支架，挂起来，然后点击这个根骨。
So you can see this root bone here is not moving. So this animation won't work.
所以你可以看到这根骨头是不动的。所以这个动画不会起作用。
And for that I'm going to go to this CR in the map.
为此，我将转到地图上的这个CR。
Then open back this animation, click this add in sequencer back to control rig.
然后打开这个动画，点击这个附加的定序器回到控制钻机。
And click this button. And now I'm going to start to adjust this animation.
然后点击这个按钮。现在我要开始调整这个动画。
So delete this redundant track and click play.
因此，删除这首多余的曲目，然后点击播放。
So this is what I have. I'm going to scroll back to the first frame.
这就是我所拥有的。我要回滚到第一帧。
Then select this root control. I'm going to select this location X to this rotation yaw.
然后选择此根控件。我要把这个位置X选为这个旋转偏航。
And I'm going to delete all these keys in here.
我要把这里所有的钥匙都删除。
Alright, first I'm going to move this root bone up.
好的，首先我要把这根骨头往上移。
So in order for this animation to work, it's important that our root bone is always below the hips and behind our feet.
因此，为了使动画发挥作用，重要的是我们的根骨始终位于臀部以下和脚后部。
So I'm going to move it backwards a little bit, somewhere near here.
所以我要把它向后移动一点，在这里附近的某个地方。
Then click this add key.
然后点击此添加键。
Alright, the starting position looks good enough.
好的，起跑位置看起来不错。
Then I'm going to scroll forward to somewhere near here.
然后我要向前滚动到这附近的某个地方。
And I'm going to move our root control up to something like this.
我将把我们的根控制转移到类似这样的地方。
Alright, I think this will do. And click this button to add new keys.
好的，我想这个就行了。并单击此按钮以添加新的关键点。
Alright, I think this will work.
好的，我想这会奏效的。
And right now for this animation it's too long. We don't need it to be this long.
现在，对于这部动画来说，它太长了。我们不需要花这么长时间。
So I'm going to trim out some frames from it.
所以我要把它的边框剪掉一些。
So I'm going to scroll to the part when the character reaches the destination. So somewhere near here.
因此，当角色到达目的地时，我将滚动到该部分。所以在这附近的某个地方。
About frame 24. Then I'm going to click this button here to add new keys.
大约第24帧。然后，我将在此处单击此按钮以添加新的关键点。
Then I'm going to trim this animation. So move this red line to here.
然后我要修剪这个动画。所以把这条红线移到这里。
Alright, that's pretty much it. We can always come back to readjust it if we need.
好了，差不多就是这样了。如果需要，我们随时可以回来重新调整它。
Then I'm going to right mouse button click this animation. Then create this linked animation sequence.
然后我要用鼠标右键点击这个动画。然后创建该链接的动画序列。
I'm going to place this linked sequence inside of this animation.
我将把这个链接的序列放在这个动画中。
Adjust it. And I'm going to rename it to hub-up_crlinked. And click OK.
调整一下。我将把它重命名为Hub-Up_crlink。然后单击确定。
And click this export to animation sequence.
并单击此导出到动画序列。
Alright, that's one animation done.
好了，这是一个动画制作完成了。
Alright, once I have the animation exported, I'm going to preview it.
好的，一旦我输出了动画，我就会预览它。
So go back to this adjust filter. Double click to open this hub-up_crlinked.
因此，回到这个调整过滤器。双击以打开该Hub-Up_crlink。
And you can see now our root bone is moving. So this should work.
你现在可以看到我们的根骨在移动。因此，这应该会奏效。
And next thing I'm going to go to asset details. Then scroll down. I'm going to enable root motion.
接下来，我将转到资产详细信息。然后向下滚动。我要启用根部运动。
Alright, go to file, click save all.
好的，转到文件，点击全部保存。
Make sure you do this before you adjust the next animation. Just in case you get a crash later.
请确保在调整下一个动画之前执行此操作。以防你晚些时候撞车。
Then I'm going to close this window.
然后我要关上这扇窗。
So I found out that if we directly adjust the second animation in here, we'll get a crash.
所以我发现，如果我们直接调整这里的第二个动画，我们会出现崩溃。
And to avoid that, I'm going to first reload this map.
为了避免这种情况，我将首先重新加载这张地图。
So go to content and double click the cr_animemap to refresh it.
因此，转到Content并双击cr_Animemap以刷新它。
And after doing this, we should be good to go.
做完这件事后，我们应该可以走了。
So go back to the raw folder. Double click to open this hub down.
因此，请返回原始文件夹。双击以打开此集线器。
And edit in sequencer, baked to control rig.
并在定序器中编辑，烘焙以控制钻机。
Click this button.
点击此按钮。
So first I'm going to delete this redundant track.
所以首先我要删除这个多余的音轨。
Then delete all of the keys inside of this root control.
然后删除此根控件内的所有键。
So select all of them and delete them.
因此，将它们全部选中并删除。
Then I'm going to move this root control up.
然后我要将这个根控制向上移动。
And move it backwards a little bit, somewhere near here.
然后把它向后移动一点，就在这里附近的某个地方。
Then I'm going to click this add key.
然后我要点击这个Add键。
Alright, I'm going to scroll forward to somewhere near frame 22, I think.
好的，我想我要向前滚动到第22帧附近的某个地方。
Then I'm going to move this root control down.
然后我要将这个根控制向下移动。
Yeah, I think somewhere near here should do.
是的，我想这附近的某个地方应该可以。
Then click add keys.
然后单击添加关键点。
And try to preview this again.
然后再试着预览一下。
Maybe move the root control down a little bit more.
也许可以将根控件再向下移动一点。
And click add keys.
然后单击添加关键点。
Alright, something like this.
好的，就像这样。
This animation here is already short enough that we don't need to train with.
这个动画已经足够短了，我们不需要用它来训练。
I'm going to directly create a linked animation sequence.
我将直接创建一个链接的动画序列。
And put it under this animation, adjust it.
并把它放在这个动画下，调整它。
Then I'm going to rename it to hub down underscore CR linked.
然后我会将其重命名为Hub Down，下划线为CR Linked。
And click OK.
然后单击确定。
And click this export to animation sequence.
并单击此导出到动画序列。
Alright, go to file and click save all.
好的，转到文件并点击全部保存。
Then I'm going to preview this.
然后我要预览一下这个。
So go back to adjust it.
因此，回去调整一下吧。
Open this hub down animation and skeleton tree, click this root bone.
打开此中枢下的动画和骨架树，单击此根骨骼。
So this should work.
因此，这应该会奏效。
And I'm going to also enable the root motion for this animation.
我还将启用此动画的根运动。
And that's pretty much it.
差不多就是这样。
And I got some important notes for you.
我有一些重要的笔记要给你。
So make sure you always click save all after adjusting your animation.
因此，请确保在调整动画后始终单击全部保存。
Otherwise, if you get a crash, you'll just lose everything.
否则，如果你撞车了，你就会失去一切。
And also, just to be safe, make sure you refresh your map before adjusting the second animation.
此外，为了安全起见，请确保在调整第二个动画之前刷新地图。
I found out that adjusting two animations in a row without doing this could crash our editor.
我发现，在不这样做的情况下连续调整两个动画可能会使我们的编辑崩溃。
And other than that, everything else should be pretty straightforward.
除此之外，其他一切都应该非常简单。
And same as always, you can download the animation that I adjusted in the resources drop down of this lecture.
和往常一样，你可以下载我在这堂课的资源下拉列表中调整的动画。
But still, I highly recommend you to try this out for yourself.
不过，我还是强烈建议你亲自试一试。
Alright, it's time for you to do it the same.
好了，是时候让你也这么做了。
And in the next lecture, we'll look at how we can use these animations.
在下一节课中，我们将了解如何使用这些动画。
I'll see you in the next lecture.
我将在下一节课上见到你。
[Music]
[音乐]